<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
    tools:shrinkMode="strict" >


    <string name="quick_guide">Quick Guide</string>
    <string name="help_string_image_dialog_viewer">Single touch to change the scale.\nDouble tap to zoom.\nTo exit, tap the bottom text.</string>


    <!--Sign In and Privacy Policy-->
    <string name="signin_rational_title">Reason to Sign In</string>
    <string name="signin_rational_msg">Registration gives you access to all tours and the new attraction lists.\n\nA lot of time has been spent researching the tours and I\'d like to keep them as private as possible.\n\nYou will never receive emails from B-Town… ever!</string>
    <string name="privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</string>
    <string name="privacy_policy_link">https://carcmedev.github.io/btown/privacy.html</string>



    <string name="help_intro">Welcome to B-Town Map\n\nPress and hold the map to access the user guide</string>
    <!--<string name="help_intro">Welcome to B-Town\n\nI hope you enjoy using B-Town. If you have a suggestion, let me know via the feedback option\n\nPress and hold the map to show additional options</string>-->
    <string name="help_tours">Show B-Town Tours\nHave visiting friends coming to town… take them out on a tour of the city\n\nWe\'ll be adding more tours when we find the time</string>
    <string name="help_search">Search for anything\nFood, drink, historic sites, Wikipedia and trending places at the map position\n\nAccess your favorites, history and saved Wikipedia reading lists from here too</string>
    <string name="help_tracking">Locate your position and enable tracking\n\n Touch the button to return to the previous position or touch the map to disable tracking</string>
    <string name="help_camera">Quick access to the camera\n\nWhen showing multiple items from the search menu, press to display a list of all items</string>
    <string name="help_menu">Show the navigation menu\n\nYou can also pull the menu out from the left</string>

    <string name="help_pin_drop">Press and hold an individual pins to remove it or use the pop up menu to remove all your pinned locations</string>


    <string name="help_fsq_explore_item">Touch to see address, open times, ratings, tips, photos and more</string>
    <string name="help_fsq_explore_map_all">Add a location icon of all the trending points to the map</string>
    <string name="help_fsq_explore_close">Discard these points and close this screen</string>


</resources>